Steven Komono

Prolesville, NC ≥ komonodrg@gmail.com (919) 410-8118 • github.com/Komonodrg-portfolio

SUMMARY

An IT professional of 13 years, currently seeking to land the role as a Security Network Engineer, Cybersecurity Analyst, or Project Manager. Always striving for efficient issue resolution, leans heavily on automation and AI. Being an easy communicator and team player has allowed me best to meet the needs of organizations. Possesses a generally optimistic view of the world, even while under pressure. Firm belief that all situations contain lessons of value.

EXPERIENCE

IT Support Engineer II

Amazon

August 2020 - March 2023, Garner, North Carolina

- \cdot Site IT Lead and POC for Operations Team in lieu of IT Manager presence. Attending Daily Deep Dive (Senior Operation Meetings).
- · Fielding requests/concerns and propositioning prescribed Amazon organization IT Standards across site Enterprise Leadership.
- Interviewing potential candidates (L5 and below), collaborating with HR & OpsTech IT Leadership via discussion panels on whom to bring on for posted role(s). Also conducted weekly 1:1 meetings with the team's junior associates.
- · Network & security engineering including administrating, troubleshooting, configuring, upgrading/repairing hardware & firmware (EOL) and maintaining overall oversight of all network components within site MDF & 21 IDFs (Routers,
- · Switches, WLCs, WAPs, Optic) via SIEM intelligence, surveillance via proactive trouble ticket remediation (Sim-T).
- Streamlined escalation workflows by integrating automated monitoring tools and collaborating with cross-functional teams, increasing incident response efficiency and minimizing system downtime.

Delivery Service Manager, Cloud Email Security Team - Cisco CX

Cisco (contractor)

October 2019 - June 2020, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina

- Streamlined incident escalation procedures and collaborated with cross-functional technical teams to swiftly resolve critical email security issues for enterprise clients, ensuring sustained operational continuity and elevated client satisfaction. ESA (Email Security Appliance) & CES (Cloud Email Security) SME Point of Contact, providing product consultation to Cisco vendor clientele.
- Performing scheduled & customer initiated heuristic wellness checks and auditing on customer's enterprise email stance, as well as providing granular configuration best practices.
- · Oversaw customer migration from on prem ESA to cloud based CES solutions, hybrid platform stances, as well as O365 & G-suite implementation.
- $\cdot \ Providing \ Jump \ Start \ service \ (initial \ customer \ onboarding) \ \& \ customer \ -initiated \ walkthroughs \ and \ tutorials \ to \ vendor \ in-house \ IT \ administrators.$
- · Possess sound product knowledge of complementary Cisco Security Appliances working in conjunction with the ESA platform, such as SMAs (Cisco Security Management Appliance), WSAs (Web Security Appliance), as well as subsequent security engines employed.
- Relied heavily on protocol knowledge of SMTP, DNS, FTP, SCP, SSH, TCP/IP as well as security protocols such as TLS, sender verification & antispoofing mechanisms (SPF, DKIM, DMARC), as well as sound command of Unix/Linux.

Network Consulting Engineer, Service Provider Team - Cisco CX

Cisco (contractor)

May 2019 - September 2019, Research Triangle Park, North Carolina

- Advised vendor clients on complex routing protocol deployments and configuration optimizations, addressing network stability and performance objectives for large-scale service provider environments.IOS-XR (ASR9K, ASR1K) consultant for numerous Cisco vendor client contracts (Verizon Wireless, Intel, Comcast/NBCU).
- · Performed Configuration Compliance Auditing against SLA best practice templates, leveraging Splunk & CSPC Collector imported data.
- · Seed file generation for the accurate, real-time polling of customer network device data via CSPC Collector uploads.
- Initiated Bug Scrubs for specific requested IOS-XR features at the request of clientele, leaning on industry standard protocols OSPF, BGP, MPLS primarily.
- Timely generation and proliferation of PSIRT (Product Security Incident Response Team) reporting, as well as Field Notice bulletin material to vendor customers
- Leveraging Python, Excel, & PowerPoint for Inventory report generation used for multi-million-dollar enterprise-wide device refreshes, based on EOX, SIAR, & LDOS device standpoints.

Network Engineer III Specialist - Network Engineering & Operations Team Verizon (contractor)

April 2018 - March 2019, Cary, North Carolina

- Facilitated seamless deployment and configuration changes for network equipment across multiple data centers, ensuring uninterrupted service delivery and compliance with Verizon's operational standards. Comprehensive troubleshooting, administration, & support of IDN (Internal Data Network) / VMN (Verizon Management Network), used by internal Verizon Business entities, end users, & data centers providing VOIP & network
- · Working independently, troubleshooting circuits (T3/T1, PVC), coordinating repair (RMAs) from vendor, & the complete engagement in break/fix protocol, acting as liaison, tester (loopbacks) & verifier between MCOs, field techs, and vendors.
- Dealing primarily with Cisco, Juniper, & Arista routers, switches, and core peripherals.

· Used solid understanding of networking protocols (OSPF, BGP, MPLS, VPNs, VLANs, STP, SD-WAN) in conjunction with data analytic tools & to remedy networking alerts generated via SNMP & Splunk alerting.

Cyber Security Analyst / Intrusion Detection Analyst

Perspecta (formerly DXC / HP Enterprise Services)

August 2017 - February 2018, Raleigh, North Carolina

- Drafted and distributed incident escalation summaries to stakeholders, synthesizing real-time threat intelligence with actionable recommendations for swift network defense enhancements. Scanning & identifying of vulnerabilities & malicious activity of USPS Enterprise network traffic via numerous SIEM and Network Analyzers; primary leaning on Splunk 6.3, Symantec Deepsight/Security Information Manager/Endpoint Protection, SiLK/Einstein, & Akamai.
- · Exchange spam analysis via cloud-based utilities & digital forensics of malware via Linux VMs: SIFT, REMnux, as well as Python scripting.
- · Remediation of malware on remote host systems throughout the entire Postal network via Invincea, Splunk, & foreign VPN attempt IPS/IDS alerts.
- · Also ensuring enterprise systems remain up to date on current antivirus signatures.
- · Compilation and proliferation of Daily Vulnerability Reports throughout CyberSafe CSOC.
- · Also generating Daily and Weekly Ticket Creation Reports and submission to management for a point of generated Metrics.

Telecom Wireless Network Engineer II

Perspecta (formerly DXC / HP Enterprise Services)

July 2014 - August 2017, Raleigh, North Carolina

- Drafted comprehensive site survey reports and documented network status updates using in-depth analysis of wireless metrics, forwarding findings to engineering teams and management to enhance service continuity and inform optimization strategies.
- Directly supported site personnel with troubleshooting and resolving wireless infrastructure issues related to the USPS DUIT DSS, PASS, and MPOS projects.
- · Monitored, maintained, and supported 455 WLCs, as well as autonomous APs & location sensors located at YMS & YMS Lite sites.
- · Identified wireless access point (WAP) and work group bridge (WGB) related issues via switch & router configurations; proactively resolving local Wi-Fi service outage(s) & adhering to implemented escalation procedures to appropriate group(s) for cross platform issue resolution.
- Through Cisco IOS & Prime Infrastructure SIEM analysis & alerts, identifying issues with RADIUS authentication, POE, rogue WAPs, error-disabled / disassociation from physical ports, mismatched VLANs, wireless signal strengths & authorized client devices.

Service Desk Analyst

Deutsche Bank

March 2013 - June 2014, Cary, North Carolina

- Resolved complex technical escalations by troubleshooting hardware, software, and connectivity issues, ensuring business continuity and minimal downtime for end users across multiple departments. End user account management & VPN access via Active Directory, VMWare & Lotus Notes.
- · Mobile data syncing of iPhone, Android, and Blackberry devices.
- · Support for 12,000 programs, applications, add-ins & plug-ins used within the Enterprise.

Apple Senior Technical Advisor

Apple

April 2012 - March 2013, Raleigh, North Carolina

- Resolved complex technical escalations for Mac OS and iOS users by leveraging advanced troubleshooting methodologies, consistently earning top-tier service ratings and enhancing customer retention. Profound knowledge of Mac OS & iOS operating systems
- Proven track record of both issue resolution & customer satisfaction (ranked 7th out of 480+ nationally for my last 6 weeks in rankings at my position)
- · While handling an average of just over 100 calls weekly, resolved an average of 95% of issues and tickets
- Promotion to Senior level after only 5 months as a Apple Technical Advisor.

EDUCATION

Associate of Applied Science, Networking Technologies

Wake Technical Community College • Raleigh, North Carolina • 2012

CERTIFICATIONS

CCNA

Cisco

· Currently preparing for CCNP ENCOR and ENAUTO.

Security+

CompTIA · 06/2024

· Recertified.

SKILLS

LAN/WAN, TCP/IP, VPN, routing and switching technologies, Cisco-based platforms, Juniper, Arista, Routers, Switches, Firewalls, WLCs, WGBs, and servers.

Python, Ansible

SMTP, DNS, FTP, SCP, SSH, TCP/IP, TLS, SPF, DKIM, DMARC, Unix/Linux.

IOS-XR, OSPF, BGP, MPLS

Splunk, SIEM, SNMP, VLANs, STP, SD-WAN, RADIUS authentication, POE